guardian.co.tt 2018-06-28

# Privacy Policy | The Trinidad Guardian Newspaper

Last Updated on October 12, 2012

This Privacy Policy discloses the privacy practices for Guardian Media Limited and its divisions and or websites:

Trinidad Guardian Newspaper  
CNC3 Television  
Inspirational Radio 730AM,  
Mix 95.1FM,  
Vibe CT 105FM,  
Sangeet 106FM,  
Aakash Vani 106.5FM,  
Slam 100.5FM,  
Trinidad Guardian e-Paper  
Guardian Classifieds  
<http://indepth.guardian.co.tt/>  
<http://legacy.guardian.co.tt/archives/>  
<http://www.guardian.co.tt/archives/>  
<http://www.guardian.co.tt/cleaningupthemess/>

Our mobile messaging services, Web sites and other applications (collectively referred to as the “GML Services”), and to any services that display this notice. For the purposes of this Privacy Policy, unless otherwise noted, all references to "Guardian Media Limited" include the divisions listed above. 

Please note, our Web sites may contain links to other Web sites for your convenience and information. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of those sites. We encourage you to review the privacy policy before submitting your personal information.

If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement, you should first contact our New Media Department by sending an e-mail to [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#147d7a6071667a71603a71707d607b665473617566707d757a3a777b3a6060).

**This Privacy Policy covers the following:**

What information do we gather about you?  
Registration for our Web sites  
 **Aggregate Information Collected Through Technology**  
What do we do with the information we gather about you?  
With whom do we share the information that we gather?  
What is our e-mail policy?  
How do I change or update my personal information?  
How do I opt-out from receiving promotional offers?  
Is my information protected?  
Compliance with legal process  
Children's Guidelines  
Your California Privacy Rights  
Changes to this Privacy Policy

**What information do we gather about you?**

The information we gather falls into two categories:

1) personal information you voluntarily supply when you subscribe, order, complete a survey, register for an online discussion, enter a contest or provide your e-mail address and  
2) tracking information collected as you navigate through our sites.

**Registration for our Web sites**

Anyone can view our sites, but a free registration process is required to access the full range of information and services offered across our different sites.

**Aggregate Information Collected Through Technology**

As is standard practice on many Web sites, Guardian Media Limited uses “cookies” and other technologies to recognize you and provide personalization, as well as to help us understand which parts of our Web sites are the most popular, where our visitors are going and how much time they spend there. Users who do not accept cookies from the domain "Guardian.co.tt" cannot access most areas of our sites.

Guardian Media Limited reserves the right to place a cookie on your computer with a unique anonymous number to ensure that your browser does not see the same ad over and over again, to sequence ads in a series and to measure the number of unique visitors that have viewed a particular ad or visited a particular Web page.

Most internet browsers are initially set up to automatically accept cookies. You can change the settings to block cookies or to alert you when cookies are being sent to your device. There are a number of ways to manage cookies. Please refer to your browser instructions or help screen to learn more about how to adjust or modify your browser settings.

If you disable the cookies that we use, this may impact your experience while on the Guardian Media Limited web Sites. If you use different devices to view and access the Guardian Media Ltd web Sites (e.g. your computer, smartphone, tablet etc) you will need to ensure that each browser on each device is adjusted to suit your cookie preferences.

**What do we do with the information we gather about you?**

**Statistical Analysis**

Guardian Media Limited may perform statistical, demographic and marketing analyses of users and subscribers, and their subscribing and purchasing patterns, for product development purposes and to generally inform advertisers about the nature of our subscriber base. We also use such information to allow advertising to be targeted, in aggregate, to the users for whom such advertising is most pertinent. Guardian Media Limited may share personal information within the group for analysis purposes, including analysis to improve customer relationships.

**Banner Advertising**

We may use demographic and preference information to allow advertising on our Web sites to be targeted, in aggregate, to the users for whom they are most pertinent. This means users see advertising that is most likely to interest them, and advertisers send their messages to people who are most likely to be receptive, improving both the viewer's experience and the effectiveness of the ads. We will disclose information to third parties only in aggregate form.

**User Generated Content (Comments, Forums and Reader Reviews)**

We offer Forums (message boards) as well as the option to provide comments (on articles) and post reader reviews in a number of areas throughout guardian.co.tt and other web sites. Any information you disclose when posting a message in these areas, along with your login, becomes public and may be used by Guardian Media Limited and its divisions  for online and offline promotional or commercial uses in any and all media. If you chose to post comments on this Web site, you should be aware that any personally identifiable information you submit there can be read, collected, or used by other users of these areas, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. We are not responsible for the personally identifiable information you choose to submit in these forums.

**What is our e-mail policy?**

_Account and Service-Related E-mail_ : Guardian Media Limited reserves the right to send you e-mail relating to your account status. This includes order confirmations, renewal/expiration notices, notices of credit-card problems, other transactional e-mails and notifications about major changes to our Web sites and/or to our Privacy Policy. If you have registered for online discussions or other services, you may receive e-mail specific to your participation in those activities.

_E-mails From You:_ If you send us e-mails, you should be aware that information disclosed in e-mails may not be secure or encrypted and thus may be available to others. We suggest that you exercise caution when deciding to disclose any personal or confidential information in e-mails. We will use your e-mail address to respond directly to your questions or comments.

_E-mail This Article Feature:_ guardian.co.tt readers may use this feature to e-mail links to articles (or other content such as slideshows and videos). The e-mail addresses that you supply to this service are saved for your convenience for future articles you may wish to e-mail; these addresses are not used for any other purpose, and will not be shared with any third parties.

**With whom do we share the information that we gather?**

If you have registered to one of our sites, Guardian Media Limited will not sell, rent, swap or authorize any third party to use your e-mail address or any information that personally identifies you without your permission. We do, however, share information about our audience in aggregate form.

**Is my information protected?**

Data Security: To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy and ensure the appropriate use of information, we have put in place physical, electronic and managerial procedures to protect the information we collect online. When you enter sensitive information (such as a credit card number) on our order forms, we encrypt that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL).

Guardian Media Limited offer online Credit Card payments via Paypal, Mastercard and Visa. The transactions are secured using a certified PCI-DSS Compliant third-party payment processing provider to ensure your personal details are kept safe. Payment by credit card is the fastest way to receive your order as there is no clearance delay. Guardian Media Limited does not store any credit card information on our servers.

**OTHER INFORMATION:**

**Compliance with Legal Process**

We may disclose personal information if we are required to do so by law or we in good faith believe that such action is necessary to (1) comply with the law or with legal process; (2) protect and defend our rights and property; (3) protect against misuse or unauthorized use of our Web sites; or (4) protect the personal safety or property of our users or the public (among other things, this means that if you provide false information or attempt to pose as someone else, information about you may be disclosed as part of any investigation into your actions).  

In no event shall GML be liable for any loss or damage including without limitation, indirect or consequential loss or damage, or any loss or damage whatsoever arising from loss of data or profits, or in connection with, the use of our websites.

**OTHER INFORMATION: Children's Guidelines**

The Guardian in Education (GIE) is a free service for parents, teachers and students. Any information supplied by users on these pages is used solely for participation in these activities, and is not shared or sold to third parties. If an e-mail address is provided, it will only be used for a one-time response back to the child. After responding to the child, the e-mail address is deleted. Access to the above services is not conditioned on more information than is reasonably necessary to provide the services. Because we’re concerned about a parent’s right to consent to the collection and use of their child’s personal information, when a question or letter is published, only the student's first name, grade and location appear on the site. To request removal of this information (non-personally identifiable) or to review or remove the optional e-mail address (personal information collected), please contact us via emailing the [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#721b1c0617001c17065c17161b061d003215071300161b131c5c111d5c0606).

These children's guidelines have been developed with the recognition that Internet technology evolves rapidly and that underlying business models are still not established. Accordingly, guidelines are subject to change. In the unlikely event of such changes they will be posted on this page. If the changes represent a material departure from our current practice with respect to the use of children’s personal information, the changes will be posted on this page thirty days prior to taking effect and will not affect children’s personal information previously collected.

**OTHER INFORMATION: Changes to This Policy**

Guardian Media Limited reserves the right to change this policy at any time. Please check this page periodically for changes. Your continued use of our site following the posting of changes to these terms will mean you accept those changes. Information collected prior to the time any change is posted will be used according to the rules and laws that applied at the time the information was collected. 

This is a web site of  
The Guardian Media Limited  
Our postal address is   
Guardian Building  
22-24 St Vincent Street  
Port of Spain  
Trinidad W.I.  
Telephone: 623-8870/9 , 623-7543; 625-7380/3
